Hey, guys.
Oh, yeah, thanks for waiting.
I'm really happy to be here.
I guess to shortly
introduce myself.
My name is Ted Xiao.
I'm a Senior Research Engineer
at the Google Brain team.
I've been on working on robotics
now for the past five years.
I've touched upon a few topics
including multi-task learning,
reinforcement learning.
And then lately,
just broadly thinking
about how we can scale
robots to make sure
that they can actually work
in the wild in the real world.
I guess today I'll be
talking about quite
a few different topics.
But as a first preface, I
guess the first thing to know
is that our team is
pretty massive now.
All of these projects are
huge collaborations with--
some projects have more
than 40 people working
on these for many years.
So these are large efforts.
And I'm just very fortunate
to call myself to be
on teams of very smart people.
And secondly, some of my
takes are spicier and more
controversial than others.
And so all of those opinions
are definitely only my own
and don't reflect
those of Google
or anyone else on the team.
So with that out of the way,
yeah, welcome to my TEDx talk.
So I think maybe
some of you have seen
a lot of the cool robot videos.
A lot learning videos out
in the wild these days.
But I am more excited than
ever, and it's not just hype,
I think.
I think there's been a
fundamental shift in how
researcher and robotics view
learning over the past two
years.
And I think the
shift has a lot to do
with all of the trends happening
more broadly in foundation
modeling, in large
scale internet
models across different
fields like language, audio,
and so on.
But I think my goal today
is to convey to you why
I am particularly excited about
this time today right and now.
And why there's been a very
fundamental 180 degree paradigm
shift, I think, across
the robot learning field.
And if you walk away from
this talk with just one thing
and that's you're slightly a
bit more excited about robotics
than you were before or
believe that the time is now
for these robots to really
start scaling exponentially
and doing something
really cool, I
think then my talk
will have succeeded.
Let's see.
The talk we'll have a few parts.
We're going to start
at a very high level
and just talk about why a
foundation model for robotics
at all, what that
might look like.
And the ingredients and recipe
for how we might get there.
Then we'll dive into
a few different works
pretty deeply that my
team has been very proud
of over the past year or two.
And finally, we'll go
back to the high level
and then zoom out and think
about what's next for robot
learning.
So why a foundation
model for robotics?
One sec, let me try
to hide this thing.
Oh, that's fine.
I will keep that
bar there for now.
But the top bar says why
foundation model for robotics?
Being coined here
at Stanford and I'll
use the phrases internet
scale model, foundation model,
and large language model, pretty
interchangeably throughout,
and I hope it's pretty clear.
But generally, when I'm talking
about these big monolithic
beasts that are training
on tons of data,
they have two very
important properties
that I think are quite nice.
One is emergence.
When very simple things, kind
of, work at a small scale,
they get a ton better when
you just scale things up.
More data, more
compute larger models.
And what we see here is
that when these models even
become good enough,
the domain space
of what they're good
at and able to do
starts to go
combinatorial even larger.
And here for these
two points, I would
like to suggest two blog
post I highly recommend.
One is from Jacob
Steinhardt called "More
is Different for AI"
and this kind of links
the phenomenon that we see
in other fields like physics
or biology.
For example, individual
water molecules
will behave very
differently and have
very different say
electrostatic forces,
then they start to clump up,
clump up and start behaving
as a liquid altogether.
We see this in herds of
animal, flocking patterns.
We see this in
humans in economies.
We see this all across different
fields and now even in AI,
we see models that are
doing stuff that would not
be even possible where
they at a smaller scale
but when they reach some
critical scale in size,
they start to work
really, really well.
This is documented by Jason
in his blog post, "Emergence
in LLMs", which you see this
plot on the bottom left.
Success rate across a
bunch of different tasks,
whether it's modular arithmetic
or purging question answering,
the success rate
is basically flat
until these models get big
enough good enough and then
the success rate just,
kind of, skyrocket.
And that's why I think these
are particularly exciting.
Sorry, you have a question?
[INAUDIBLE]
I'm curious to know, do
robotic foundation models
display [INAUDIBLE]?
Great question.
And I'm really glad you asked.
We have-- I'm pretty excited
to present some directions we
have along that.
I hope we'll answer
a question and maybe
about 10 minutes or so.
OK.
Yeah.
But I think that's a
question on all of our minds,
including myself.
So I think before we even
get to the feasibility
or the existence of any
robotics foundation models
like is this even needed.
And I think the argument
that I don't think
is obvious is that
I think emerging
capabilities and
relying on these
might be actually indispensable
for robotics to actually work.
A lot of the research over
the past decades in robotics
has been in one bin, one
room, one table, one robot,
one building even.
But these are so vastly
different from the orders
of magnitude more complex
while real world situations
that humans operate
in every single day.
And I think to make
that gigantic leap,
we're going to have to rely
on this emerging capability
scaling curve where
things, kind of,
work you have very kind demos.
Maybe you have a
humanoid robot programmed
to backflip after
hundreds of trials,
but going from that to
the chaotic real world,
I think we're going to have
to rely on this emergence
phenomenon for that.
And I think maybe
even intellectually
or academically it's
also interesting to think
about why or why not a
foundation model for robotics
might even work.
It's worked in so
many other domains.
There's existence proofs in
audio, music, coding language,
another domain every single
day it seems with 3D models
and beyond.
But if there is something
very special about robotics,
whether it's embodiment
or causality or physical
grounding, and that is
the barrier to making
this very simple
recipe that's work
in all these other domains.
If there is something
special about robotics
that causes this
recipe to fail, I
think that's quite interesting
to study why that is.
I'm personally an optimist.
I don't think there is some
magical secret sauce that's
going to keep robotics
from being tackled
with the same formulas
and recipes that's
worked elsewhere.
But I think this
is a question I'd
like to find out the answer to.
And so maybe then,
instead of just motivating
this philosophically, OK,
we need foundation models.
Foundation models are great.
Let's try to build
one for robotics.
How do we actually do that?
Well, I think we can
leverage a few ingredients
by standing on the
shoulders of giants
and looking at other domains.
The first one is looking at
different design principles
of ML scaling from
other domains.
Let's look first at high
capacity architectures,
the topic of this class today.
Ideas such as self-attention.
As all the different ideas
encompassed in the transformer,
as Andre Karpathy
famously said, it's
like a magical universal
differentiable computer
that's very general, very
robust, and very remarkably
scalable on many
different dimensions.
Let's use those.
We should also leverage
the more guiding principles
that have been seen the scaling
laws, the trends this year--
Chinchilla.
We not only have to
scale the model size.
We also have to scale
compute and we also
have to scale the
number of unique tokens
in the corpus of the vast
data sets that we train on.
But if we do all
three together, this
has been shown to reliably
have a pretty good chance
of succeeding no matter what
domain you're looking at.
And finally, what
that kind of means--
and I think this is actually
going to come up later.
--is that data set size
seems to matter these days
a lot more than quality.
Even if you have some
sentences on Wikipedia that
are misspelled, or
some falsehoods,
or some things that
aren't so desirable
if in aggregate your data
set is diverse enough
and interesting
enough, these things
will hopefully wash
it out in the mix.
Ingredient number
two, the proliferation
of the internet scale
models themselves,
not just the principles.
What's exciting and I'm
sure it's definitely
been very shocking for both
experts and laypeople alike,
is that a lot of these
generative models
across many different modalities
have been experiencing
emergent capabilities
and have been
surpassing all of our wildest
expectations time and time
and again.
But even when we think
that we're exhausted.
All this stuff is too much.
That's not going to work.
Something will come
out and completely
blow me out of the water.
And I think this trend will
definitely keep continuing.
And I think in addition to
that, they not only will
continue coming on and
accelerate more rapidly,
they're going to happen with it
whether or not we do anything
in the grand scale of speaking.
Me as a robotics
researcher or you
and whatever subfield
you're on, there
are parts of machine learning
that likely you'll probably not
ever touch in at
least the near future.
And those parts will be seeing
tremendous breakthroughs
and scaling and new
capabilities coming
online every single week.
And you can look
at this not only
in the impressiveness
of the models but also
the acceleration of progress.
The time scales in
which new models
are being released where large
collaborations are being worked
on by many groups and then
being available to access
for all to use and build upon.
And the final
ingredient in this trend
is more of a robotic
specific one.
But it is a vast shift from
online robotic learning, where
robots collect experience
online make actions and learn
through trial and error
to an offline setting,
where we decouple
the data generation
process from the data
consumption process.
As we've seen in all these other
foundation modeling domains,
these big internet scale
data sets are so diverse.
And they're static.
We just scrape them once or
scrape them multiple times
continuously but we
aggregate a continuous pile
that's just growing.
Here we see either the
pile data set from Eleuther
or a LAION-5B for
paired image text.
And these are pretty big.
And they're orders
of magnitude more
than what we've seen before.
And they are definitely
a key ingredient
to why other domains have
been doing so well by training
these big foundation models.
Coming back to
robotics then, I'd
like to take a brief detour
into how the shift came to be.
Because it's very easy
to say in a sentence,
yeah, robotics is
offline more than online.
And this is coming as, kind of,
a no brainer to many folks who
are coming from other
domains like this is the way
things are done.
But in robotics, this has
been a very big shift.
And I think robotics
has also been
synonymous with
RL, reinforcement
learning for a lot of people.
And I think increasingly,
this is becoming less true.
And so I'd like to take
you down a brief trip
down the history of my team.
The other slide of the
talk is brief history
of robotics at Google.
Yeah, of course, thanks.
And I think this is not just
for dramatic exposition.
It's really to try to guide
you through how drastically
our team's thinking has, kind
of, evolved over the years
and how that's going
to inform the design
decisions and the kind of
risks and research directions
that we take in this
specific project.
So I'm going to show coming up.
Thank you.
So in 2016, some of
you may have seen this,
we had what we
call the arm farm.
Seven Kuka robots in a room,
collecting picking data 24/7.
And this was doing on-policy RL.
In the real world, we were the
first team to kind of say, hey,
can we even do this?
With the goal of saying, can
we do end-to-end robot learning
with results in the real world?
This was, kind of,
risky at the time.
It was not a common take.
And from that we developed
several interesting research
directions that we
started exploring.
We looked into
stuff like QT-Opt,
which is a cue-learning method
working on continuous control
actions while taking
vision inputs.
We worked on
CycleGAN to transform
simulation-based images
into real-looking images
for [INAUDIBLE].
We looked at
concurrent role, how
we get robots moving
faster and more
efficiently in the real world.
I'm sorry, do you
have a question?
Yeah, [INAUDIBLE] 24/7 data
collection [INAUDIBLE]..
Curious to know, how
did you read seven?
Yeah, great question.
And that one, I
think, was basically
the arms would pick
stuff up from the bin.
If they messed up
and it fell out,
well, we'd come back
the next morning,
and there'd be objects scattered
all throughout the room.
So there was no reset.
But if they missed a
little bit, the objects
would fall back into
the bin and, hopefully,
be in a position where they
could pick them up again.
I wanted to ask you
if you can repeat
the question they've asked.
Oh, yeah, of course.
Thanks.
I'll do that in the future.
This specific question was,
for this 24/7 arm farm,
how did we do resets?
And the answer is,
well, we didn't.
We designed the bin
so that they were
banked so that if an
object slightly missed,
they would fall back in the bin,
reorient themselves, maybe add
more diversity with
the training data.
But this was doing
off-policy online RL
row with cue learning.
And we mixed it with same
data, deploy it again.
Next, we went through this
consolidation phase around 2020
when we were like, all right.
This is pretty cool.
But we want to get
out of the bin.
How do we do more complex tasks
in a more practical setting
that could be
closer to something
that humans would want to use,
that's more general every day?
There, we settled on this office
micro kitchen environment,
if you've heard of the
famous Google micro-kitchens.
And I think this was the setting
we decided to operate in.
And there, we started
collecting data.
We scaled our operations.
And there we scaled approaches
to some different things.
And I think, in the
bottom right here,
is the more mechanized
reset version, I would say,
of the arm farm.
Here, we had a bin
that folded in half.
And this was doing multitask
RL in the real world.
And the bin would flipping
in half, dumping objects
from one side to the other.
So you could do more
interesting tasks,
whereas the arm farm
was, pick anything up.
Now we could say, hey,
pick up the carrot
and place the tomato
onto the plate.
And then the bin would
flip, and you'd reset.
Some other works we
look at multitasking
imitation learning.
This is BC-zero.
And then, we also look at stuff
like combining reinforcement
learning with imitation learning
bootstrapping [INAUDIBLE]..
But in 2020, once
again, we realized
we were working in a ton
of different directions,
and we wanted to consolidate.
And I think the two main things
that were really bothering us
at the point, at the time, were
we are hitting two main walls
across all these methods.
Some of them were plateauing
at this 50% to 70%
rough range in the real world.
And other methods were
requiring very specific data
distributions.
They had to be on policy,
or they could only
use demonstrations, or
they blah, blah, blah.
There were so many different
nuances and gotchas
to all of these
different methods
and all of these
different drawbacks.
And so the question
we posed was,
we're open to any
method, any strategy that
will enable us to solve tasks
in a very performant matter
manner, more than 90%
in the real world,
and, also, that can scale
with some kind of data
that we can collect.
And maybe this is a bit
more lax than, let's say,
an academic setting where you're
much more resource-constrained.
But at the end of the day,
even our team does not
have infinite money, we
still have a certain number
of robots, a certain
number of operators,
and we're constrained
by the laws of physics.
So we need some way
to acquire more data
that we can then learn from.
And so we're all
scratching our heads
thinking about this for a
few months in spring 2022.
We decided on going with
multi-task imitation learning.
So this was a vast departure
from the 24/7 arm farm.
This was a vast evolution of
how we approach the problem.
We found that with enough,
no gentle care and love,
multi-task imitation
learning was
able to hit these 90% numbers.
And it was able to get better
with more demonstrations.
These aren't the
cheapest thing, but it
was able to scale with
additional demonstrations,
which was a sign of life
that we were looking for.
So that brings us to
less than a year ago,
our team was deciding
this is the path forward,
at least in the
near-term future,
but maybe, we could
just think about how
the approach we were
taking here might also
spread out in the future.
And we might be able to bring
back these other threads.
For example, if now that we're
decoupling this data collection
of demonstrations, or
et cetera, from how
we learn from them with a
multitask imitation learning
policy, maybe we
can, in the future,
then do something
like offline RL.
But I think at a
high level now--
I've just, in a
few short minutes,
just compressed six years
of very bitter lessons
that our team has been learning.
And I think, from
where we are today,
and looking back even
just two years ago,
if you told me that the
strategies we're deploying
today could just scale
the way they are,
I probably would not
have believed you.
You have a question?
[INAUDIBLE] instead of
trying to figure out
how [INAUDIBLE] data sets.
Great question.
So I think task conditioning
is definitely still-- was
an open question at the time.
But I think with
this work, BC-zero,
we found that language
was able, at least
in a templated language
representation,
was good enough where
we could direct.
I think BC-zero
is over 80 tasks.
So they were very templated,
like pick grapes, or move
grapes onto a plate,
or drag this across--
drag a cloth across a table.
And I think this
representation was still enough
where you're learning a
good number of skills.
You're passing in, essentially,
a one-hot ID into your policy
network.
And it will learn
to imitate that.
And for each one
of those 80 tasks,
it'd collect hundreds or
thousands of the imitations.
And we'll touch upon the
specifics of that a bit later,
too.
So yeah, today, or at least in
2022, let's do offline methods.
Let's decouple data generation
from data consumption.
And let's take these
three lessons now
that we've touched upon.
Let's take the design
principles of ML scaling,
and then figure out what
lessons can actually
be applied when you go--
look into the future
for a recipe for robot
learning and foundation models.
The first lesson I think
is very important is
this high-capacity
architecture, is like attention.
The second, I'll
touch upon later,
is data interoperability,
tokenization, discretization.
And the second ingredient
is the proliferation
of these models themselves.
Can we leverage them because
they will get better over time?
And I think here, I
would like to plug
my colleague Karol
Hausman's bitter lesson 2.0,
which is the bitter lesson.
The first one from
Richard Sutton
was, you should leverage methods
that scale with more compute.
And maybe in
today's day and age,
the lesson is that we
should leverage methods
that are able to
utilize improvements
in foundation models because
they're going to get better.
Yeah.
So both in the bitter
lesson 1.0 and 2.0,
one thing that's
always unclear to me
is suppose I have
a set of methods,
and I want to choose
the methods that
are going to scale with more
compute or, in this case,
scale with better
foundation models.
The question is,
how do I actually
decide which of those
methods meets those criteria?
Yeah, a great question.
I think, and maybe it's--
and I think that's a very--
I don't have a good
answer for that.
Could you repeat the question?
Oh, sorry, yeah.
The question was in bitter
lesson 1.0 and bitter lesson
2.0, the question is,
well, that's great.
That's the lesson.
But how do we
actually decide which
methods meet these criteria?
And I think my answer is
it's not always obvious.
And it's actually
quite tricky sometimes.
But maybe, sometimes what-- you
can be very confident that, Oh,
yeah, this will definitely scale
with more data and compute.
And some that are the same--
basically, the more
hard-coded you are,
the more assumptions, the more
heuristics you make bake in,
the more you-- in
our day and age,
the more you rely on a
specific implementation
of a specific foundation
model of a specific class
of algorithm maybe that will be
less robust than a method that
just assumes some very abstract
input and output and assumes
that how you get from
that input and output
can improve over time.
And maybe the algorithm itself
even changes altogether.
So I think that would be my
take on the bitter lesson 2.0.
But this is definitely still--
I think the jury's
still out on this.
And my basic-- one of the
things I like to propose
is that language
is the way that we
can leverage bitter lesson 2.0.
If you have language as the
universal representation
through which all
of these foundations
communicate to each other,
whether it's captioning,
or generation, or
whatnot, I think
that's one way that we could
leverage bitter lessons 2.0.
And finally, the
third ingredient,
offline robot learning,
decoupling data generation
from data consumption.
Putting these all
together, my recipe
for how one takes
at a modern attempt
at embodied
intelligence would look
like would be to combine
these large offline data
sets with high-capacity
architectures
by using language as
the universal glue.
And in the works I'm
going to present shortly,
all of our different projects,
I think, in some way or another,
are inspired by this philosophy.
And now, that we've understood
the motivations and potentially
one possible approach--
Sorry.
Can you go back one slide?
Of course.
The bottom, the recipe--
"large diverse offline data
sets with high-capacity
architectures using language
as a universal glue"--
I'm curious to know which, if
any, of these are currently--
[INAUDIBLE] is not
the right word.
Which of these are limited?
Got it.
Because it seems to me like we
already have large offline data
sets.
We have high-capacity
architectures.
Those architectures
[INAUDIBLE] language.
It seems like we already have
all the components necessary.
So why is this then
not a solved problem?
The question was, it
seems like we have
a lot of these ingredients.
And so, why hasn't
robotics been solved yet?
So I would argue that actually,
this take here, and maybe I'm--
this is to the wrong
audience at the moment.
But I think this is
not very non-obvious
across the robotics field.
Many people do
not agree with all
of these, much less two of these
or even any of these points.
And so I think-- and
also the existence
of the scale of how mature
each of these components
are within robotics is
that very different stages.
And I would say-- and we
can talk a bit later about,
for example, data scale
or the architectures that
have diffused through
osmosis from other ML domains
into robotics, but
I think we're still
at very different
stages on how much
people have actually
bought into these lessons
and invested in them.
Can I have a follow-up question?
Yeah.
[INAUDIBLE]
I'm curious to know--
I'm not asking you to name
names, but the people who
might not be buying into all
these pieces [INAUDIBLE]..
Yeah, I can probably--
I also don't want to get
into too much trouble here.
I'll probably get
myself in a bit
of hot water in a few slides.
So I'll expand
upon it a bit then.
Sounds good.
Yeah.
I'm just curious to know
what their opinion is
and why you think they're
wrong on the subject.
[INAUDIBLE]
Yeah.
And I would say that
me, personally, and--
I'm not speaking for my team,
but a lot of people on my team
are probably at the very extreme
end of learning, scaling,
data-driven, foundation
model-based, let's go big.
And I think a lot of
people don't believe that,
and, yeah, happy to discuss
why later, maybe after the Zoom
as well.
[LAUGHTER]
So yeah, well, OK, then
let's go ahead and dive in
and see how this recipe
might actually percolate
into specific domains.
And the first one is RT-1.
This is a recent
work from our group
that works on how we can
scale imitation learning.
And let's look at
how we can actually
apply these first principles.
So the first one is to
consider what we actually--
let's put ourselves into
the spring 2020 mindset.
We've been collecting
demonstrations for a while.
This is a ton of
demos, like 100,000.
Data was collected
over a year and a half
on many, many robots
on many, many tasks.
That exists.
It was expensive.
And over time, this
will actually not
trickle up at insane amounts.
We won't just get 100,000 new
high-quality demos every day.
This will grow over
time, but it's not
going to grow for free.
And autonomous
ways of doing this
is very hard, as you
saw earlier with ntop
with the bin reset
mechanism, or DeepMind
has a record
RGB-stacking, where they
try to do autonomous resets.
And the way that we're doing
it right now, or at least
for this paper, was
human teleoperation
pioneered by BC-zero.
And that was very
expensive as well.
So there's going to
be limited throughput.
And finally, BC-zero used
a ResNet base backbone.
And it was pretty
good, but they found
that it was very sensitive
to training distributions.
For example, when they remove
data from some teleoperators
to make the data
more homogeneous,
performance got better.
And that's not really
a property we like.
We want more data, even if
it's not exactly the same.
So the lesson here,
models need to be robust,
and they need to generalize.
Cool.
So we have, models need to
be robust and generalized.
What else do we have?
Well, off-the-shelf
models are pretty slow.
If we take in these
huge vision transformers
from other domains, they're not
going to run on the real robot.
We need to be able to run
at a pretty high frequency.
They need to be reactive.
Inference time needs to be
slow because all our models are
vision-based.
And finally, we want our data to
be able to understand language.
As I mentioned, if language
is the universal glue,
our data set already
has some language.
And we want eventual models
to be very multi-modal.
This is first principle
that we need to bake in.
What does this mean?
We can't just take
something existing.
We probably need to design
or at least modify something
from the ground up.
And let's take the best
practices that we've
seen work in other fields.
And so we worked for a bit.
And we came up with this
architecture for RT-1.
Again, once again,
this is a large team
with a bunch of
different contributions.
And I'll just go through
a few of them here.
At a high level, RT-1
is robotics transformer.
It operates at three hertz.
It takes in visual
input from the robot,
or RGB camera, as well as
natural language instruction.
There the image is
petrified and fed
into a film-EfficientNet
tokenizer.
It's then passed
into token learning,
which I'll talk about soon.
And then also the language
instructions are tokenized.
And then, they are put
into the same transformer.
And then, finally, we output the
discretized actions as tokens
and send that to the real world
in three hertz in a closed
loop.
This transformer
is a decoder one.
We use a sparse categorical
entropy objective
for action prediction by
applying a causal mask.
We use the pre-trained
EfficientNet backbone.
And we also use token
learner for very--
for faster inference.
Diving a little bit deeper--
Oh, sorry.
Yeah, a question?
[INAUDIBLE]?
Great question.
So the image token, when it
goes in from-- so each image
is the high-fidelity RGB
image from the camera.
We split that up into
81 separate patches.
And so each patch is--
it's spatially just
like the square there.
But the cool thing is that
what TokenLearner does here,
this thing here, is-- it's a
previous work from our group
that takes in a bunch of
possible image patches
and dynamically selects
which of those image
patch tokens are more
relevant for the task at hand
given the existing context.
So from those 81
image patch tokens,
we sub-sample eight of
them to use for inference.
And this happens at
every time stamp.
And that process has learned,
which of the eight patches
are relevant at
any given moment.
And otherwise, we're sending
in way too many tokens.
And the context
length would explode.
And we wouldn't be able
to do inference on robots.
We are also passing in a single
sequence length of six images.
History is quite
important when you're
doing temporally coherent
tasks in the real world where
things like physics and exactly
this nuanced detail of what
the objects are doing in
relation to each other
and to your robot those
details really matter.
And in total, the model size
is 35 million parameters,
which is quite a bit
smaller than a lot
of these other huge
internet-scale models.
And finally, one main difference
here is action democratization.
Before a lot of the products,
we are doing continuous control.
And if you think about
it, our robot does have--
We do end effector post
control or position control.
And they are-- the real world
is a continuous state space.
And to do that,
we had to come up
with many algorithmic novelties,
for example, a CEM actor that
did basically sampling of
these continuous action spaces
to propose the highest
ones that would
get rated by the Q function.
And we do this twice,
blah, blah, blah.
But that's so sensitive.
But we needed to do that
to get things to work.
But now, we just decided,
let's just bin our actions.
It's only 256 discrete actions.
And let's just predict
those as tokens.
Any questions?
Yeah, what I was
going to ask is--
so I heard you mentioning
that you have this design
requirement or engineering
requirement about speed,
latency reaction.
I think we say that
that necessitates
having a relatively small
model, which makes sense.
But one of the
lessons of scaling,
when we're talking
about foundation models,
is that [INAUDIBLE] bottleneck
by either data or parameters.
So I guess what
I'm curious to know
is how do you balance
these off in the sense
that you want to have lots of
parameters that have a really
powerful model, but
on the other hand,
you want to have
very [INAUDIBLE]??
Yeah, great question.
And to repeat it,
the question is,
we set a pretty hard
constraint with 100 millisecond
inference time, yet,
a lot of the lessons
in foundation modeling is that
you shouldn't be constraining
yourself against any dimension,
whether it's data set size,
compute or model capacity.
And I think my
initial answer to that
is that's a very great
point and something
I think that's going
to be coming up
as a severe bottleneck
in the future.
But for our initial
case, I think
this is more of an exploration
of whether these principles
and even scaling,
well, beyond what we
were looking at now to work.
Already, this 35
million is gigantic
compared to a lot of prior work
using, for example, a ResNet
34 or whatnot.
So this is already much bigger
than a lot of other options.
And maybe, for now, at
least, it's the easiest.
It's the largest scale
we could go to, roughly,
in the short term without
having to think of more tricks.
[INAUDIBLE]
I guess that's more
just an [INAUDIBLE]..
Got it.
Yeah, we can talk
about it a bit later.
Maybe I think I'd also love
to hear your thoughts, too,
because it's very
non-obvious how we can get
past some of these bottlenecks.
So what [INAUDIBLE] this.
Say I give you [INAUDIBLE],, but
everything else is the same.
The data is the same.
Requirements are the same.
Do you think we see
significant improvements, even
some emergent behavior
[INAUDIBLE] pipeline
for these bigger models?
Or do you think
there's more to this
than just scaling down and
reliability [INAUDIBLE]??
Yeah, a great question.
We ran some ablations
on model size.
I might have that
in a few slides.
But maybe we can
return to that then.
And if not, we--
I can--
[INAUDIBLE]
Yeah, but a great question.
So yeah, that's
the architecture.
And I'll discuss some of
the ablations to the trends
later on.
But maybe this is
a robotics lecture.
I should show you
some pretty visuals.
So let's look at some
evaluations we did.
We compared against
some baselines.
One is GATO, which you
might be familiar with.
And then other--
the other one is
BC-zero, the ResNet baseline.
And we find that we evaluate on
seen tasks versus unseen tasks.
And we also add in various
distractor objects.
Our normal data collection looks
like this top-left picture,
three cans on a gray desk.
That's basically it.
But then we push it further by
bringing in a lot more objects
so that the table is
so cluttered that even
as a human, sometimes it's hard
to find the object that you're
actually looking for.
We add in tablecloths to make
the textures very different.
We bring it to new micro
kitchens, with new surfaces
altogether.
And we find that RT-1
is more robust than
these other different methods.
[INAUDIBLE] this
model on this layout?
Or would the GATO be only
trained by this specific robot
hardware?
Good question.
The question was from the GATO.
Was the GATO model
trained on our data,
or was it just already
included in GATO?
The answer is this data
was not included in GATO.
And so, we retrained the
GATO model only on our data.
So here's just a
different visualization
of the robot going out
in our micro kitchen
and doing different
interesting things.
You can see here that it's
trained on one setting,
but then it goes into
a brand new kitchen,
brand new countertops,
new objects,
and it's able to do all
of them pretty robustly.
We also put it into a
long-horizon setting
using the SayCan framework
that we'll talk about next.
But in these settings,
a lot of them
are mixing all of these
generalization capabilities.
And on the plot-- on
the left here, we're
using what we call
generalization levels inspired
by the VIMA paper that
would basically increasingly
change more factors of
variation simultaneously.
And here, we found RT-1
is the most robust.
[INAUDIBLE]
How do you [INAUDIBLE]?
Yeah, a good question.
We'll go into a bit
more detail later.
But I think at a high
level, teleoperators
get a structured
template command
of like, verb, noun, verb, or
something, like "pick coke can"
or "move apple near sponge."
We have around 700
tasks set up this way.
And they go ahead and collect
that data, press Done.
And then later we
have-- we make sure
that successes are
actually successes,
and we discard stuff
that's unsafe, for example.
[INAUDIBLE]
Oh, yeah, I got
it for this paper.
We utilized 130,000
demonstrations for this, yeah.
[INAUDIBLE]
Is there any [INAUDIBLE]?
Yeah, a great question.
I think a lot of
prior work has also
noted that when you have, for
example-- oh, the question was,
did you find that the
trajectories in your data set
were very multi-modal?
And I think what you mean by
that is that to go from point A
to point B, I can go
left, or I can go right,
or I can go straight.
And I think this kind of
diversity in, basically,
for a single image
state, but yet, my data
has three possible
labels, that can have
very bad effects sometimes.
For us, I think, because
we are using teleoperator
demonstrations, the data was
more homogeneous than perhaps
in the wild.
For example, there's a type of
data collection called PlayData
where operators just
do whatever they want,
and we label in hindsight.
And I think our data is
more homogeneous than that.
But we did not find
a lot of the issues
that we've seen
in prior projects.
One potential answer is maybe
it's the architecture itself.
But we can talk
about that later too.
Yeah, a question?
[INAUDIBLE] when it comes to
terminating actions, how do we
determine [INAUDIBLE]?
That is great question.
We actually do have
a termination action.
So the policy itself,
the-- so the question was,
how do you determine when
an episode is complete?
And the policy is able
to predict-terminate
because at the end of each
teleoperation session,
the operator can click
a button, and it's smart
as the episode's done.
[INAUDIBLE]
Yeah, I think for
these evaluations,
we were quite strict.
But definitely, I
think in some cases--
maybe if we're just doing
an experiment for ourselves,
we'll have a dense
reward scale of grasp
the object and move
closer, grasp the object
and almost got there
but mess up at the end.
And we'll have a grading
curve, basically.
But for all of these
stats I'm showing here,
it was zero or one.
One, fully complete.
Zero was not fully complete.
And I think what
was exciting, maybe
talking about the
multi-modality aspect is then
we pushed the
limit even further.
We decided to train on very
diverse data distributions.
Your math background, yeah.
OK.
So right now, you saw
130,000 demonstrations
train on this everyday-robot or
preparatory mobile manipulator.
But we were also looking to
train on very different data
distributions with very
different action distributions,
very different trajectories,
even very different visuals,
objects, tasks.
And to do that, we included
two other data sources.
One was simulation data, which
was our robot but [INAUDIBLE],,
but it looked quite different.
And also, this
data was collected
with reinforcement
learning and not
with teleoperator
demonstrations.
In the past, with all the IO
plus RL work that I mentioned,
we found that combining
these two types of data
was going to be very
difficult because RL data has
very short actions.
It's very quick.
That's very optimized for
the specific reward function
versus human-collected
teleoperation data
is a lot more
human-like, so to speak.
And finally, we revived a
data set from many years
ago, in 2018.
If you remember
the KUKA Project,
that arm farm has now been
operational in that state
for many years now.
But we had that data still.
And so, we were hoping to
see if a different robot
with a different action
space on different objects
with different visuals
in a different building
could still be combined with
data from this macro kitchen
data set that we
trained on originally.
And what was very
surprising to me
is that RT-1 was able to
learn from all of these very
diverse data distributions.
I had never seen a result like
this or any other architecture,
for example, a ResNet or
even another learning method,
like reinforcement
learning, could successfully
learn on such different data
distributions so robustly.
And we evaluated, for example,
on combining concepts.
So we would have the original
everyday-robot robot pick up
objects that were only
seen in the KUKA Project,
or we would put objects
only seen in simulation
and see if our policy
could understand that.
So it did seem like it could
generalize between objects
that's seen in other
data sets and concepts
that it had seen
in other data sets
into the setting it was in
now in the real micro kitchen.
And that was a very fun result.
[INAUDIBLE] has a question.
How did we combine the action
spaces of the everyday robot
with the KUKA?
Great question.
Yeah, we just
tokenized the image
so that the tokenization
scheme was interoperable.
But I think that was the--
yeah, I can dive into
that in a bit later too.
OK.
Yeah.
And note that does
not mean we can't
send the exact actions
for one robot to another
and have it execute.
It was more just like--
in the data set, I think,
even by human inspection,
you can tell that
these are coming
from two different robots.
So yeah, let's look at some
ablations for the scaling loss
that we're all here for now.
We found that reducing data
site size reduces performance,
but more interesting,
maybe, is tasks
diversity was quite important.
Here, we have two
different trends.
The green line is
what happens when
you reduce the total amount
of episodes per a task.
And then gray here--
the purple curve
is for what happens
when you reduce
the total number of tasks.
And we found that
having more tasks
is relatively more
important than having
more data for each task.
And I think this was a lesson
that I think is probably
going to suggest ways that
we should scale robotics
even further.
It's not to just collect
more data of the same task
in the same settings but
to go out into the wild
and get more diverse behavior.
Quick question.
How do you define
diversity in the data?
Great question.
The question is, how do
you define data diversity?
In this case, it's
just a number of
unique structure-templated
commands
that teleoperators receive.
So those 700 templated commands,
when we start reducing them
and only train on 500 or
only trained on 300 of them,
performance drops much
quicker than if we
had taken the same proportional
cuts to the total number.
Yeah.
OK.
So I guess I'm very [INAUDIBLE].
It seems almost [INAUDIBLE]
tipping point [INAUDIBLE]..
Yeah, I don't think we--
the question was
there seems to be
almost a linear correlation
between a data size and success
rate.
And I think we could
apply some fancy scaling
law, trying to curve fitting.
But we didn't look
too much into that
because this is a
trend that we expected.
We just weren't sure
about the magnitude
of how much it would affect us.
And I think I don't have
any really good insights
on this besides that we see
this phenomenon empirically.
Yeah.
[INAUDIBLE]
It would seem that [INAUDIBLE]
there should be less
[INAUDIBLE] make this
100% or [INAUDIBLE]??
Great question.
So the question
is, Oh, maybe this
will just go on indefinitely,
or is there something
magical about January 2023?
But I think this is maybe also--
This is when we
start to conflate
the algorithmic exploration with
the practical considerations
of scaling real-world
operations, which was,
we got enough data, our
policies were hitting,
saturating on these
hitting close to 100%.
We're like, all right, let's
collect another data set.
So we basically collect
until it's at 100
and then we switch
to something else.
But at this point
what was interesting
is that we bet really big
on this RT-1 architecture.
We'd already been collecting
demos for a while.
So it was possible that we had
collected more than we needed.
And in some cases, actually,
you could cut tasks
without losing too
much performance, which
was quite interesting.
[INAUDIBLE]
It says it needs
[INAUDIBLE] data
that might be more diverse among
the different tasks [INAUDIBLE]
the same task?
Yeah.
If you just use the same
object for all the tasks
or the same [INAUDIBLE].
Great question.
And the question
is whether or not
all tasks are created equal
in terms of their capacity
and entropy for
different behaviors you
can learn from them.
And yeah, that's
definitely true.
Some tasks are much easier.
We have a task that's just
"pick up this object."
That's going to have much
less interesting stuff
you can squeeze out of it
than removing something
into a drawer and then
closing the drawer.
That's, yeah, a great question.
Great.
Now, ablations, we also trained
without the big model size.
We did it without
pre-training, without--
with continuous instead
of discrete actions,
with autoregressive
actions, without history,
without the transformer.
And I think all of
these design choices
did seem to be required
for robust performance.
[INAUDIBLE]
Oh, yeah, of course.
Yeah, I think all the--
and, again, for
paper writing, it's
the best thing that we
can empirically find.
That's the method.
And then, we'll figure out why
each of these are important.
And so, yeah.
I think one surprising
thing here, perhaps,
was that autoregressive
actions hurt.
You might think that
passing in more information
is always better than
passing in fewer information.
But in this case,
maybe conditioning
on your previous actions was
doing in-context learning.
It was doing online
systems identification
to figure out what teleoperator
this data came from
and how you can overfit that
specific set of action history.
And so removing that
was actually better,
one interesting tidbit there.
Cool then.
And maybe in the
interest of time,
I'll try to get through the
other ones a bit more quicker.
And then we can
maybe just do a few,
or I'll just do the
questions at the end
if that's possible,
just so we have
time to get through everything.
The next work here, moving a bit
away from skill learning then,
and actually on to
the planning level,
I think the first project
took a lot of the design
principles of other fields
and all this offline robot
learning paradigm and put
it into the skill learning.
So it actually bring
that out to other parts
of the robotic system.
And the first work
here is SayCan.
If you remember here, back
in this timeline, in 2022,
we started thinking
about, Oh, yeah, how do we
scale this multi-task imitation
learning, but at the same time,
large language models and other
types of foundation models
are really picking
up steam, whether it
was imaging or DALL-E 2.
And we definitely
wanted to figure out
how we could use those as well.
We had come up with
this [INAUDIBLE] design
that we're betting big on.
But from here, we
started to explore how
all of the bitter lessons 2.0--
we could start utilizing
foundation models
within the context of
our full stack system.
The problem of
doing this naively
is that language models
are not completely
a very natural fit for robotics.
For example, if you're
a robot in a kitchen,
you ask the language
model, "I spilled my drink.
What can you do?"
Language model will give you
stuff that's not very relevant.
It's going to ask
you to vacuum it,
it's going to ask you
to call a cleaner,
or it's going to apologize.
And these are not
things that the robot
can do in your kitchen with
your spilled drink to help you.
And so there are two
parts of this then.
The one issue is that
our robots are limited.
They are very constrained
with what they can do.
They cannot do everything.
But they can do certain things.
And then the second problem
is that the language models
are also constrained.
They don't know
what the robot sees.
They don't understand that
they are in a robot body
in a micro kitchen,
needing to do real stuff
in the physical world.
And so, we need to get the
robots to speak language model
language and then the language
model to speak robot language.
To do this, we present SayCan.
In the same setting, "please
put an apple on the table."
We score the predictions
of the language model
on a constrained
set of tasks that we
know the robot has
been trained to do.
And then, we also take
the affordance function
from the robot.
And the affordance function
is an estimation of,
given some kind of state,
what the robot is able to do,
how confident it is that it
can successfully accomplish
that task in the given state.
In our case, we use something
like a value function
for reinforcement learning
which accomplishes this quality.
Given these two values,
these two scores,
we have the confidence
from a language model
and then the confidence
from the robot.
We can combine these.
And then, hopefully,
the combined prediction
is both something that's
going to be very semantically
relevant for the
high-level instruction.
Finding an apple
is the first step
and, "please put an
apple on the table."
But it's also something
that the robot can do.
There's no robot in
the frame, but it
knows that it's been
trained to find an apple.
So it can navigate
around to find it.
And so, hopefully, we can do
this then in a closed loop
and then keep on
going and predicting
a high-level plan from
the language model
that's grounded with the
affordance function of what
the robot understands.
There's a video here of the
SayCan doing different stuff,
but happy to share
it later offline.
It's very cool, trust me.
It's the greatest thing
since sliced bread.
And, yeah, some numbers, then.
We tested this out on very
long-horizon instructions,
encompassing more than
10 separate navigation
and manipulation skills
in the micro kitchen
that you see on
the bottom right.
We evaluated hundreds of
different evaluations on this.
And we tested out very-- a
lot of different concepts,
including things like rephrasing
by using single primitives
by drawing instructions that
just came from colleagues
and friends.
And then we found that
while they were failures
in both the language model
planning stuff side, where
it would predict the wrong
path for the current situation,
as well as on a policy execution
side, even when it gets
a good plan, the robot
will mess up sometimes,
overall, it was still
doing quite well.
And now, let's kick
this back to the lesson.
I think this is a very
great example of how
we can leverage internet
scale foundation
models as they get better.
When we started the project, we
started with a language model
called FLAN from Google.
Throughout our
implementation, our PaLM
came online, Pathways
Language Model.
And when that happened, we were
able to just hot-swap it in.
And performance just
got better for free
without us having
to do anything.
By just assuming that
language was the API,
the plan just has
to be any string.
It can come from any source.
It can come from a human.
It can come from
a language model.
When we improve
that language model,
the system gets better overall.
And here you see,
with a scaling size,
as the model LLM
increased in size,
our planning performance
got even better.
And some cool tricks here
to get it working, well,
how do we actually
produce this plan?
Well, while just by prompting
as is the rage these days,
with chain-of-thought and
with better prompting, of just
giving it examples of, here
are some great robot plans,
now give me a new
plan starting with
this high-level instruction.
We saw that the robot
could do all things,
from understanding different
languages to asking them
to do very complex
reasoning, like hey,
give me something caffeinated
or "I don't do caffeine anymore.
Get me something better."
Or bring me a healthy
snack versus bring me
an unhealthy snack.
So they can was able to
reason through all of these.
But I think that was our kind
of the first contact of robotics
with language
models on our team.
And it was the first
exploration into how
these two worlds could overlap.
There were definitely
still improvements, though.
And in Inner Monologue, we
try to improve those further
by bringing in vision
language models.
The idea here is that we
had a very high planned rate
success with SayCan,
but unfortunately, it
wasn't really able to
recover from failures.
What I mean by that is that the
language model would not really
get updates of what was
going on in the world.
So that if this was the plan
it proposed, go to the table,
pick up a coke, bring it
to you, but you messed up
picking the coke can,
you drop it on the floor,
it would still continue
trying to bring it to you.
Put it aside.
But all of that does not
really matter anymore
because you drop the coke can.
And so, in this work,
Inner Monologue,
we are really
hoping to figure out
how we could add
closed-loop dynamic feedback
from the environment into
this planning process.
Let's take that
exact same example.
Now, instead of just directly
correcting every instruction,
maybe we add back some
feedback from the scene
also conveyed using language
as the universal API here.
The scene can tell you
what's actually in there.
Maybe the robot asks a
question now in the robot.
This is the language model
asking the clarification
question.
Maybe hear a human response
or another language model,
then you can predict the
action or the next task
to do once the language
model has enough context.
And maybe you even add in
stuff like success detection,
and so on and so forth.
How do we do this, then?
Well, the first thing
that we implement
is what we call passive
scene description.
Just using either an
off-the-shelf engineer
heuristic, using object
detection models,
something like ViLD, you can
describe the scene in text
and just convey all of that
context to the language model.
For active scene
description, this
is maybe similar to
visual question answering
if you're familiar
with that field.
The language model can
actually propose active queries
that it's curious
about in the scene,
maybe to make sure that it
has enough context to move on.
And here, either a human
can provide the answer,
or in the future, a VQA
model, as they improve,
can provide that.
And finally, for
success detection,
this is very important to allow
the language model planner
to know when to try
to retry something.
Here, we take in the first
and last image, fine-tune
a [INAUDIBLE] success
detector, and use
that to provide binary
success/failure information
back to our language model.
And for the--
Results wise, we can see a very
similar SayCan long-horizon
evaluation, but
here we actually--
what's interesting is
that we're able to--
and basically implement all
of these different automated
feedback mechanisms
on the robot, and so
that it's able to reason
and recover from things.
Here, you see, it's going
to try to go to the table.
But the humans actually
have been saying, hey,
I changed my mind.
And then it changes-- the
human change its mind again,
asking it to go back and forth.
And the robot's able to-- maybe
we're torturing the language
model at this point.
But the language is able
to replan and make sure
that the human
intent is satisfied.
We also tried.
I'm not sure if
this video shows it.
But situations where we did
adversarial inputs where I
walked around and just--
knocking objects out
of the robot's hands
and forcing the success detector
to tell it, hey, you messed up.
Try again.
And we also tried
this out on a couple
of different domains, a
simulated tabletop manipulation
domain as well as a real-world
manipulation domain.
And we found that
this was much better
than SayCan or, let's
say, just only using
visual features themselves,
with something like CLIPort.
And I think here, it really
speaks towards a trend
that I really come
to appreciate.
In 2018, a robotics
professor once
said that when they looked at
all of the different things
preventing robot learning
from scaling tremendously,
they thought the bottleneck was
high-level semantic planning,
about reasoning,
about common sense.
And I think in 2022 and
2023, language models
can provide one path of
how this can be offloaded,
at least in the interim.
And I think if language
models are the API,
then you can just bring in
these vision language models.
As object detectors get
better, as success detectors,
as VQA, as language
models get better,
you can bring them
all into the fold.
And the act is a life vest.
If your robot currently does
not have common sense reasoning,
these other models can act
as a scaffold in a life vest
to bring you up to par with
what they currently love.
And maybe then, in
the future, you'll
get beyond what the
language models know.
But in the short
term, it does seem
that we can leverage
them to accelerate what
we can do in the real world.
Moving on now from--
we saw now how language
models could do planning.
We saw how vision language
models could help planning.
And now, we're going
to switch gears a bit
and think about how
vision language models can
help other aspects
of the bottlenecks
that robot learning faces.
One of these is that data
collection is very expensive.
As we mentioned before, we
did have this 130,000-episode
demonstration data set, but
it was collected over a year
and a half at significant cost,
both in resources and time,
and money and with
many, many robots.
And, of course, these tasks,
too, we're also a bit limited.
We use 700
very-templated commands,
instructions that we would give
to teleoperators because we
knew that this would scale.
If we collected enough data for
each of these templated tasks,
we could do that specific task.
And here's the flow that someone
was asking about earlier.
We give this "pick
coke can" instruction.
The operator controls the
robot in the real world,
finished the task, marked
steps that it has terminated,
and then, stage that out to
this big orange data set.
And that big orange
data set is what
we trained on and all
of the previous projects
for the control policies.
What we additionally
considered was
adding a bit of crowdsourced
hindsight annotation.
If you're familiar with
Hindsight Experience Replay
in reinforcement learning
with goal-conditioning with--
maybe the robot did
something that wasn't just
this high-level
template instruction.
We could ask a human to
describe more verbosely what
the robot did.
Maybe it picked up
the coke can that was
on the right side of the table.
Maybe it picked it up
and then knocked it over.
Maybe it moved it very
slowly to the middle.
There's a lot of semantic
diversity encompassed
in this demonstration
that is not totally
caught by this
high-level templated
"pick coke can" instruction.
So we labeled 3% of this big
orange data set with these very
verbose descriptions.
And next, we applied the
pseudo-label strategy
that's been seen in other
fields, such as video
pretraining with their
inverse dynamics model.
But instead, we apply
that to the instructions,
to the semantics of what's
contained in your data set.
So step one, we be
pre-train a clip model
on your small labeled data
set of 3% of your main data.
Then, you go ahead and use that
trained-VLM data to label all
of the templated instruction
demonstrations that you had
before that
130,000-episode data set.
And now you have a
relabeled data set
which has a large diversity
of interesting semantic
constructions.
And then, we plug in all of
these data sets into RT-1
and just train a
language condition
behavior cloning policy similar
to how we would normally.
Even though normally we just use
data set B, the orange one, now
we use all three data sets.
And then, finally, we evaluate
on entirely new unseen
instructions.
In the prior works, we were
evaluating mainly on these 700
templated instructions.
But in this work, we
actually go beyond that.
We can type in almost
anything you want
that you think might succeed.
And you can phrase
it how you can.
You can add typos.
You can even do it by
referring to semantic concepts.
You can add spatial concepts.
And we see how it does--
The reason that this
might work, maybe
visually to represent
this, is here
are the [INAUDIBLE] embeddings
on the left and the right.
It's the same embeddings,
but on the left,
they're colored by the original
templated instruction that was
used to collect that episode.
And on the right is what
the vision language model
thinks if it's allowed to put
a free-form natural language
caption and assign
it to that episode.
You see that on the left,
you have these big clusters
of "pick coke can."
It's like hundreds or
thousands of episodes.
But we all just call
them "pick coke can."
On the right, then we can then
expand those concepts and say,
actually, this episode is
picking up the red coke can.
This episode is picking
up the clumped coke can.
This is picking up the coke can
that's next to the chip bag.
And so you can get
a lot more mileage
out of the same underlying
data set by just using language
as the diversity mechanism
through which you
expand the concepts
that you're considering.
And, for example,
in the middle, you
see "open top drawer" can
become "hold and pull out
the top drawer."
We have stuff like
"the center-left"
for the middle episode.
For the bottom one,
"pick green rice chips
from white bowl" becomes,
"lift up the grape chip bag
from the bowl bow and
drop it at the bottom
left corner of the table."
So you get a lot of these
semantic, spatial concepts that
are now going to be in your
target supervised labels.
Yeah, a question.
Yes.
So using [INAUDIBLE] this
is expected [INAUDIBLE]..
You have your [INAUDIBLE].
Yeah, great question.
So I guess, if I
can rephrase a bit,
the problem is
that it's actually
a very difficult and
perhaps even intractable
problem of how you map all the
linguistic concepts you see out
in the wild down
to maybe embodied
specific types of episodes.
And here, maybe I would say
is that we are definitely
introducing a lot of our
priors and our biases
onto maybe what we call as left,
you mean left 10 centimeters,
left two centimeters.
What do words mean?
And these definitions,
what do they
mean to us, to the
crowd compute raters
that generated these captions?
What do they mean to the robot?
What do they mean to
the language models?
Maybe these are all
slightly different.
But the hope is at least
if they're roughly similar.
We'll get directionally
correct improvements.
So I would say the nuances
of these specific hard lines
of definitions and
actual semantic meaning
of these words, I think that's
maybe out of scope right now,
but maybe something
we'll dive into further.
At a higher level,
though, I think,
basically, the bar
is just so low.
We have these 700
template instructions
that are basically one-hot IDs.
And we just want to make those
closer to natural language,
even if by a little.
And I think, at
least, we're trying
to get towards that with these
visual language models that
are captioning automatically.
I hope that answers
your question.
And we also compare
it to a few baselines.
On the top left,
here, we look at what
if we only train on this 3% of
these fancy human-rated labels.
What if we only train on
the original RT-1 data sets?
What if we train
on both of these?
And what if we train
on both of these,
plus all of the predictions
given by our VLM?
And what's interesting
here is that relabeling
seems to universally help.
We evaluated only on
novel instructions
that was new for this project.
It's the first time on a
robotics project where we only
tested it on something--
I could type whatever I thought.
I'd type it in, and that
became the test set.
And we just have to make sure
that it was never contained
in the training coverage.
And you see all these
interesting examples
on the right here of stuff
like "move the lonely object
to the others."
I have no idea how this worked.
Stuff like lifting
the yellow rectangle,
talking about colors,
talking about "move
the right apple to the left."
Here, we actually had
two apples in the scene.
And actually, in our
training demonstration data,
we never collected scenes
with duplicate objects.
Just because we thought of
this multi-modality problem,
if you just say, "pick coke
cans and these two coke cans."
It's going to be very difficult
to figure out which one to do.
But with language labeling,
it seems like maybe we
could do that now.
So even though we never trained
on scenes with two apples,
now you could evaluate on them
and just specify with language
which apple you want to go for.
And it was working
pretty reasonably.
And finally, for
the last example,
here, I thought it
was interesting,
a coke can-- we try to
do a novel behavior.
A push towards the left was
not a templated instruction.
We only had "move coke can near
Y," where Y is another object,
"move coke can near apple.
Move coke can near your sponge."
So pushing this motion, of
just pushing the coke can
into the air essentially
was not something
that we ever encompassed.
But maybe it was in
one of the labels.
Maybe if you've seen like
"move coke near apple"
and the apple is on
the left, and you
saw "move coke can near sponge,"
and the sponge is on the left,
you would generate the model,
could generalize and be like,
oh, left means this side of the
table, not a specific object.
So maybe that's
what's happening.
But it's very unclear.
This is, as I
said, just I type--
I thought of something, I typed
it, and just saw what happened.
And we definitely hope
to explore this more
quantitatively in the future.
Bottom left, of
course, is, I think,
comparing against
non-visual augmentation.
So maybe you can also get
these interesting concepts just
from language alone.
Here, we had adding random
noise, or we do Matlab style,
just swapping out
words, or we even
use LLM GPT-3, in this
case, to propose rephrasing
of existing instructions.
But I think my takeaway
there is that you really
need visual grounding for
the visual language model
to say, actually, yeah,
this caption is factually
accurate at this
given point in time,
and that it's something
perhaps that would
be interesting for a robot.
That fine-tuning process
provides both of those.
Yeah.
[INAUDIBLE]
Yeah, definitely.
These are just some subsets
of type of these evaluation
instructions, but we
had over 60 of them.
We didn't do a full quantitative
ablation, for example,
as we did in RT-1.
We had this seen
and unseen task set,
and that was compositional.
You'd see, "move
coke near apple,"
and you would see, "move
apple in your sponge."
But we'd hold out "move
coke near sponge,"
and we'd test that out.
But in this case, I think we
can go much more beyond that.
Because our language is
completely free-form.
The compositional space
of what you can combine
is just going to be much larger.
So we did try a little bit.
To answer your
question, we tried
some combinatorial evaluations,
but there's definitely
a lot more thoroughness
that we could do there too.
How am I doing on time?
OK, 10 minutes.
Maybe I'll try to wrap
up pretty soon, then.
The DIAL Takeaway then is
that two parts, lesson 2,
leverage foundation models.
Let's use VLMs as
data augmentation.
And lesson 3, let's make sure
that our offline data set
is robust enough where these
different behaviors exist.
And you can describe
them in language.
If you don't have enough
diverse behaviors,
no matter how good
your labeling is,
you probably can't elicit all
of the interesting concepts
that you want to learn from.
And maybe most exciting for
me here was that, actually,
some label noise is OK.
Notoriously in supervised
learning and imitation
learning, you need
very clean labels
that are always 100% true.
You don't want to be learning
from noisy data where some--
a large percentage
is just not accurate.
But in our case, it seems
that some label noise was OK.
The vision language
model was not
always predicting factually
accurate descriptions
of the scene.
And I think this
definitely hurt when
it got too high, the noise.
But at smaller
levels, it definitely
still seemed to be OK and
robust enough to handle that.
So that was a deep dive then
on some individual works that
use this big recipe of language,
foundation models, offline data
sets in different parts
of the robot system.
And this was the pitch
at the beginning.
And I hope you at least see a
little bit of how our team has
tried to take these
principles and apply them
to accelerating robot
learning in the real world.
As we see, these different
types of ingredients and lessons
map onto different parts of
the robot system altogether.
But it's still learning.
That was RT-1 that
we talked about.
For planning, that was SayCan.
And then adding the
close of feedback
with vision language models,
that was inner monologue.
For low-level control, we
didn't talk about this today,
but exciting work from
our team is actually
using language models
to predict code
that's executed on the
robot directly, perhaps
as low-level controls.
Language models,
they read textbooks,
they read-- they've
read raw ROSS docs.
They've read UR5
documentation code.
And they can write
code for these robots,
and we can execute that.
For data augmentation,
we saw DIAL
with vision language models.
And also, I didn't
talk about this here,
but for object-centric
representations for things
like feature activation
maps for specific objects,
we can use those as
task representations
for mapping a scene.
And in NLMap, they did that
for object-centric navigation
around the micro kitchen
that we looked at.
And I think, hopefully, in the
next coming weeks and months,
we have a few more rows and
entries to add here as well.
But I think this kind of mindset
is a very exciting research
direction of how you can apply
these big high-level concepts
about foundation models
and offline data sets.
And you look at what exists
in the robot systems of today.
And you find many gaps in
opportunities still available,
where we can do everything
from exploratory pilots
on how this might look
all the way to more
extensive evaluations and really
building out robust systems.
I think both of
these have value.
So I'll conclude
with just saying
that it was very
fun exploring all
of these complementary
directions.
But there are still
some major questions
of how we can take these
concepts even further
in how these trends
and ideas might even
evolve moving forward as
foundation models get better,
as more data set becomes
available online,
as more data becomes
homogenized and tokenized,
and interoperable.
And I think a lot
of the concepts
from other fields like
linguistics and vision,
and from all of the big
scaling level questions
that are being pioneered in
language-based foundation
models.
Hopefully, those ideas can
trickle down to robotics.
Maybe even robotics can
provide something back
by providing embodied action
causal data sets that maybe
might improve the
quality of reasoning
of some of these large language
models that are not embodied.
With that, though, I guess
I'd like to thank everyone
for your time and for--
Dave and [INAUDIBLE]
for inviting me
and open to any questions about
the papers or just at a high
level as well.
Thanks so much.
A question?
[INAUDIBLE]
Yeah, a great question.
So the question,
I guess, is what
about tasks that require
more semantic reasoning,
like operating at a certain
speed or with maybe,
I don't know, numerical
reasoning within the question,
the prompt itself?
I would say, so for a lot of
the more common sense reasoning,
like "throw away three
coke cans after another,"
I think the language model is
very good at that right now.
So for, the second
planner, it will
predict "throw away the coke
can" three separate times."
For the low-level
skill policy learning,
though, I think that's more of
a high variance, I would say.
And definitely,
for right now, we
don't really condition on
speed or how you do it exactly.
But that's definitely--
maybe something
like that we could do.
If you could relabel with like
"pick up the coke cans slowly"
versus "pick up the
coke can quickly,"
maybe that is something a visual
language model could recognize.
Yeah.
There is [INAUDIBLE]
combinatorial generalization.
So if you have data
[INAUDIBLE] something, if you
hvae something [INAUDIBLE].
A great question.
The question was,
what scale do we
see combinatorial
generalizations start
to occur, maybe between--
you've seen colors of one block,
and then you want to
evaluate on a new color.
And I think that's
a great question.
And unfortunately, my answer
is going to be very vague.
And it depends.
It depends on how you
define your tasks.
It depends on the
scale of your data set.
And it depends on the
concept that you're
trying to generalize across.
I think there have been numerous
attempts to basically formalize
what it means to
generalize within learning
and within robotics, even
within the specific settings we
consider.
And I don't think there are
any clear trends of where
you can say, Oh, yeah,
this is the number
I need to hit where I can
generalize across X, Y, Z
dimensions.
You could evaluate
all of those, but I
don't think it will help you
predict new trends, at least
right now.
I think we're probably--
this is just me talking.
I would say where one order
of magnitude off before we
can start to make very broadly
generalizing statements
about generalization
capabilities.
But I think add one or two more
zeros to our data set size.
And we can start to
talk about that in terms
of tasks and object skills.
[INAUDIBLE]
Yeah.
So say [INAUDIBLE].
So we thought of an [INAUDIBLE].
Yeah, a very astute observation.
So the question was that in
SayCan, the value functions
that predict these
scholars on the right
here for the
affordances are only
scoring a certain
limited number of tasks.
So is that the bottleneck?
And I would say, yes, 100%.
Scaling the number of tasks
that your system is able to do,
that you can then
give to the planner
as its buffet of options to
choose that is the bottleneck.
No matter how good your
planner is, if you can only
do three tasks, there's
only certain combinations
of those three tasks
that it can do to map
onto a high-level instruction.
So as you add more tasks, as
the low-level skill capabilities
of your robot increase,
you're adding precision
to the coverage of the
high-level instructions
that your robot can try to do.
And that's one of the main
bottlenecks I see today.
[INAUDIBLE]
Great question.
So have we tried RT-1
with ROHF or with RL.
I think the short
answer is I think
we have some stuff in the
works that is doing that.
But right now, for
all of our projects,
currently, we're just using
this imitation learning loss.
Again, I think I view
this multi-task imitation
that we're making as kind
of an existence proof.
It works.
It's not cheap.
But it does work.
And it does scale.
And that, at least, is
a good starting point.
And our main hope over
the next months and years
is, can we improve beyond that?
Can we add back in
offline improvement?
Can we add in RL back
to the equation somehow?
I'm an RL person at heart,
so I really hope so.
[INAUDIBLE]
Sorry, could you repeat that?
[INAUDIBLE]?
Yeah, a good question.
So regarding task balance
and whether text-only data is
sufficient for helping
model controlled learning,
I think my hope is
that when models--
when we experience the emergence
in both the robotic space,
and we've already seen
emergence in the language space,
at some point maybe
these reasoning concepts
will start to transfer
between the two.
I would point them to one
interesting paper, which
is, I think, "Can Wikipedia
Help Reinforcement
Learning," from Shane
and some other folks.
They pre-trained a
large policy network
on autoregressive
token prediction
on Wikipedia, just text only.
And they use that to initialize
control for Atari Games
with RL.
And this actually helped.
So maybe this is philosophical,
but maybe there's
something about
decision-making reasoning
that transfers between
text and action data.
[INAUDIBLE]
Great question.
I definitely agree.
Passing in six
images is not going
to be enough when
you're executing tasks
for minutes at a time.
Like "clean my whole
house," and then
you can only pass in
the last two seconds.
Come on.
So I think that's
definitely going
to be a limitation
as our tasks get
more complex and long horizon.
And I think here, it's
another open question, too,
is context when we have high
dimensional images, even
with token learning for
reducing the number of patches
that we pass through.
It's still very
high dimensional.
And we quickly hit the
context length cap.
Can we do-- how do we
improve it beyond this?
Maybe it's like retrieval
transformers or some other kind
of mechanism.
[INAUDIBLE]?
Great question.
I think we are hoping to
explore that in the future.
But with this context
length limitation,
we are already near the context
length capacity with just
the six images alone, much less
passing in whole trajectories
of zero-shot behaviour--
few-shot behavior we wish
to see.
So TBD.
Yeah.
[INAUDIBLE]
Cool.
Thank you, guys.
Thank you.